

CAREER PROFILE

Since graduating with my degree in Environmental Science, I have explored many of the fields related to my degree, but have finally found the one I am most passionate about, GIS and Cartography. I was hired by the Wisconsin State Cartographer's Office as a student GIS developer during my first semester in the GIS certificate program and have worked there throughout the program. I intend to continue down the path of development, but I also have a passion for agriculture applications, remote sensing, and conservation biology.



EXPERIENCES

GIS Developer

2016-Present

Wisconsin State Cartographer's Office

Investigate and Implement a workflow to process and prepare Landsat data and images obtained from the Amazon S3 Cloud provided by Amazon Web Services for use over large study areas in the state of Wisconsin Maintain the Public Land Survey System database and webmap applications as well as the Control Finder applications on the SCO website. Links on homepage to both of these maps.

Introduced to and proficient in PostGRES, SQL, shell scripting, python, html, css, and javascript.

Assistant Editor for About Place Journal 2015-2016

Black Earth Institute, Wisconsin

Review and asses submissions via submittable. Help maintain database of submitters and donors as well as assist in website layout management for About Place Journal and Black Earth Institute.

High School Hockey and Softball Coach 2014-2017

Baraboo High School, Wisconsin

Apply knowledge from years of playing to coach JV and Varsity players



SKILLS & PROFICIENCY

Windows and Linux Environments

HTML & CSS

Adobe Illustrator & Photoshop

ArcMap, QGIS, Carto, & Mapbox

Python, SQL, Javascript

Amazon Web Services (AWS)



Dawson Pancroft-Short
GIS Developer/Analyst



bancroftshor@wisc.edu



608-370-1687

EDUCATION

GIS Certificate
University of Wisconsin Madison
2016-Present

Bachelor of Science in Environmental Science Chatham University 2008-2013

Languages

English (Native)
Spanish Basic (3 years)
Swahili Basic (3 years)

Interests

Hockey
Drumming
Cooking
Gardening
Sailing